Andrew Moss

Pasadena, CA | (626) 374-6106 | drew.moss86@gmail.com | github.com/drewmoss86

SUMMARY:

I am an analytical person with 4+ years of experience as a Business Analyst. More recently, my interest and passion for technology led me to a technical recruiting agency where I gained extensive knowledge and insight into how technology drives innovation in differing industries. This gave me the opportunity to speak and meet with technology leaders, contributors and disruptors in hundreds of organizations, large and small, across multiple states. I now wish to find an organization where I can leverage my technical experience, strong communication skills and analytical background to help drive the business forward.

EDUCATION:

California State University, Fullerton

BA, August 2009

Major: Business Administration with a concentration in Finance

Pasadena City College

CIS Certificate In Progress

Courses Completed: Fundamentals of Computer Science Science I & II in C++

SKILLS:

- Microsoft apps: Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Access and Outlook
- Programming languages: C++, Python, Java, HTML5, CSS3
- IDEs: Visual Studio, Qt, Atom
- DBs: MySQL
- Human languages:
 - English verbal and written fluency,
 - Chinese (Mandarin) verbal fluency
- Other tools: VirtualBox, Vagrant, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE:

SEP, Inc.. - Los Angeles, CA

April 2013 – Present

3 Practice Manager/Technical Recruiter - Boston, MA/Los Angeles, CA

- Lead and mentor a small team of recruiters in both Boston and Los Angeles that helped tech startups and Fortune 500 companies identify and onboard top-tier technical talent
- Assist with training and developing of new staff members
- Track personal and team sales numbers, month-over-month and year-over-year, using Excel
- Negotiate and renegotiate contracts with new and existing clients
- Evaluate new businesses to ensure fiscal viability
- Dispel false assumptions and misinformation between candidates and hiring managers

2 Assistant Practice Manager – Boston, MA

- Started a brand new technical staffing office in Boston with two other senior recruiters from Los Angeles
- Helped grow the office from 3 to 10 people

1 Associate – Los Angeles, CA

- Made 100+ outgoing calls per day to prospective candidates and hiring managers to sell our recruiting services
- Have high-level discussions with businesses in various industries to understand business requirements, company pain points and reasons for the open positions
- Learned about various aspects of software development and IT from the SDLC and Agile/SCRUM to network and system infrastructure with various automation tools and programming languages

Lumina Media (formerly i5 Publishing) - Irvine, CA

October 2011 - March 2013

Sales and Operations Analyst

- Created and analyzed sales reports to discuss with sales managers prior to quarterly sales manager meetings
- Compiled reprint reports, analyzed sales data and made reprint suggestions to the CFO on a monthly basis
- Designed new reporting methods for a few of the monthly reports
- Tracked and reported digital media sales data directly to the company President every month
- Generated sales reports for accounting statements
- Produced ad hoc sales reports for my supervisor and sales managers
- Imported magazine and book POS data from customers into our ERP system for sales orders

2 Credit / Collection Specialist / Accounts Receivable

- Worked with A/P Managers and company CEOs and found unique solutions to tactfully bring accounts current
- Performed account risk analysis using our aging and D&B to present to the Director of A/R on a weekly basis
- Assigned credit limits by analyzing sales volume, history, and sales rep evaluation report Coordinated
 activities between customer service and sales reps to resolve billing disputes and discrepancies
- Proactively maintained over 100 accounts and established excellent working rapport with customers

1 Purchasing Allocation Analyst

- Analyzed data in ERP system to determine purchase quantities and initiate inventory exchanges worldwide
- Allocated inventory to nationwide distribution centers based on the regional sales demand and DCs capacity
- Coordinated product logistics between domestic and international vendors and our freight forwarder
- Contacted 20 domestic vendors and 10 international vendors to resolve daily shipping and receiving issues
- Met with vendor sales reps on a quarterly basis to discuss pricing, logistics and quality control issues
- Prepared reports to help with inventory management and accounting, e.g. In-Transit, Back Order and Late PO,
- Compiled status report for the company president and responded to his inquiries
- Led the team that developed the shipping/receiving section of the Vendor Compliance Agreement
- Interfaced with Accounts Payable and reconciled the discrepancies between the PO Price and Invoice Price
- Assisted with cycle counts and physical inventory on a regular basis
- Determined appropriate materials and supervised the repackaging of bulk goods

RuffaloCODY – Anaheim, CA

January 2008 - December 2008

Professional Fundraiser

- Called prospects for donations to colleges, hospitals, and national public radio stations
- Generated daily pledge tally and prospect request reports for supervisors
- Conducted telephone surveys for non-profit organizations
- Trained new representatives to use fundraising software and in telephone communication skills

Genesis Commercial Capital – Irvine, CA

May 2007 - January 2008

Account Specialist

- Maintained account database for senior account executives
- Cold called prospective clients for senior account executives, made follow-up calls with prospective clients
- Assisted the senior portfolio manager with collection efforts
- Reviewed and analyzed credit reports from the three major credit reporting agencies as directed

LEADERSHIP:

Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America Troop 620

REFERENCES:

Will furnish upon request